# Shanon Wambui

Software Developer

## About

Nairobi Kenya 00100 KE

shanonwambui24@gmail

in shanon wambui

Shanon wambui

# Web Development

#### Master

HTML CSS Javascript

**Typescript** 

# Back-end engineering

## Intermediate

Python Node.js Java

#### Database

## Intermediate

MySQL NoSQL

## Cloud

## Master

Amazon Web Servives

# Deploying

#### Master

Docker

## Frame-works

#### Master

Angular React

#### Languages

English (Native speaker)

## Interests

## Wildlife

Ferrets Unicorns

# Summary

Proficient in software development with over 1 year experience in building crossplatform frontend applications. My main area of interest is creating user interfaces that are intuitive and flexible because I have a passion for technology and a want to be successful as a software engineer. I am committed to making the most use of my knowledge and experience to develop software solutions that not only satisfy functional needs but also deliver outstanding user experiences.

# Experience

\_\_\_\_

Numeral IOT deals with everything IOT related. From speed governors to smarthome appliances

Software Developer intern

Successfully developed and deployed highly responsive and user-friendly websites that offered an exceptional user experience. The websites were built using Typescript, incorporating modern technologies like endpoints for seamless data communication. By leveraging advanced features provided by Chrome extensions, the websites capabilities and user interactions were enhanced.

- In the development process, Angular and TypeScript were employed.
   TypeScript's strong typing capabilities greatly contributed to the readability, maintainability, and efficient error detection of the codebase. By incorporating decorators and static typing, the development team was able to leverage advanced features that further enhanced the software's robustness and efficiency.
- Collaborated with the back-end software engineer to develop and deploy software applications such as an ecommerce website where clients can order food online and a checkpoint website where clients can report cases such as land cases

## Open Source Projects

**E-commerce website** http://41.242.2.189:2111/business An e-commerce website where people can order food online.

Javascript endpoints responsive Chrome Extension Docker

- Developed a highly responsive and user-friendly website that provided an
  exceptional user experience.
- Designed and built the website using Typescript, incorporating modern and cutting-edge technologies such as Google Maps integration, JavaScript, and endpoints for seamless data communication.
- Leveraged advanced features and functionality offered by Chrome extensions to enhance the website's capabilities and improve user interactions.
- Utilized Docker for seamless deployment

## Checkpoint website

04/2023 - 07/2023

02/2023 - 03/2023

01/2023 - 04/2023

A checkpoint website where people report cases.

# API cookies

- Developed and deployed a fully functional website with user authentication
- Utilized cookies to provide personalized user experiences and facilitate session management on the website.
- Integrated payment APIs to enable secure online transactions, ensuring a smooth and reliable payment process for users.
- Employed endpoints to establish effective communication between the website's front-end and back-end components, allowing for efficient data transfer and processing.

# Smart walking stick for the visually impared

03/2023 - 12/2023

Automating walking sticks to aid the visually impared in their navigations.

Sensor technology and its application in detecting obstacles and hazards

- Wireless communication systems for transmitting notifications and location information
- Microprocessor programming for integrating sensors, buzzer, and transmitters

# Education

# Jomo Kenyatta University of Agriculture and Technology

09/2018 - 12/2023

Bachelor Electrical and electronics engineering

# Volunteer

# Kenya Space Agency

01/2022 - 01/2023

Taifa-1 Sat student trainee

Student training program to develop a Nano-satelite

- I was part of the EPS (Electrical Power Supply) team.
- Designed and implemented the Power circuit

# **Society of Engineering Students**

01/2019 - 01/2023

Member

Engineering program for students in engineering related fields.

• Took part in tech workshops organized by Women in Tech committee.

# References

I am delighted to recommend Shanon as a software developer. Her exceptional performance in her role demonstrated her proficiency and dedication. Shanon's ability to tackle complex problems and deliver high-quality solutions makes her a valuable asset to any company.

- Brian Munene